It's been a long time coming.
TAYLOR SWIFT | THE ERAS TOUR is a music film directed by Sam Wrench.
A concert film documenting Taylor Swift's record-breaking Eras Tour (2023-2024).
Filmed during the Los Angeles shows, the film captures the tour's ten acts,
each representing a different musical era from Swift's career.
The film showcases over 40 songs, elaborate stage
productions, and Swift's performance.
Self, played by Taylor Swift.
Self - Co-Band Leader, Guitar, Keyboards, played by Mike Meadows.
Self - Co-Band Leader, Guitar, Keyboards, played by Max Bernstein.
Self - Guitar, played by Paul Sidoti.
Self - Bass, Keyboard Bass, played by Amos Heller.
Self - Drums, played by Matt Billingslea.
Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour is a 2023 American concert film produced by the
singer-songwriter Taylor Swift and directed by Sam Wrench.
It documents the Los Angeles shows of the Eras Tour (2023–2024), Swift's sixth
headlining concert tour and the highest-grossing tour of all time.
Swift struck an unprecedented distribution agreement with AMC Theatres and Cinemark Theatres
for the film after negotiations with the major film studios fell through.
Filming took place in August 2023 across three shows at SoFi Stadium in Inglewood, California, with a
budget of $10–20 million and SAG-AFTRA permitting production to proceed amidst its 2023 strike.
Swift announced the film later that month, catching studios off guard and causing the release dates
of several films that had been set for release on or near October 13 to be moved.
The unconventional release strategy was a topic of media discourse; many journalists and industry personnel praised Swift's move to bypass the
studios to partner with theatres and opined that the move defied the traditional producer–distributor–exhibitor model of releasing films.
The film premiered at the Grove in Los Angeles on October 11, 2023,
and was released to theaters worldwide on October 13.
It was met with significant ticket demand, amassing a record $37
million on its first day of pre-sales in the U.S.
and over $100 million in total global pre-sales.
The Eras Tour became the highest-grossing concert film of all time,
earning $267.1 million in its limited theatrical run worldwide.
It received acclaim from critics, most of whom praised the direction,
spectacle, energy, and Swift's artistry and showmanship.
An extended cut of the film, subtitled (Taylor's Version), includes performances withheld from the
theatrical edit and was released on the streaming service Disney+ on March 14, 2024.
A second concert film recorded at the tour's final show on December 8, 2024, in
Vancouver, was also released on Disney+ on December 12, 2025.
Subtitled The Final Show, the film was directed by Glenn Weiss and featured The Tortured Poets
Department act that was incorporated into the tour's setlist after Wrench's film was released.
The film explores themes of musician, live performance,
pop music, concert film, singer-songwriter.